hi all good evening good evening guys am I audible and visible guys give me
thumbs up thumbs down do you feel any disturbances voice of fan do let me
know if you okay hi Abhishek good evening
so how's everyone doing is everyone good anyone got placed like recent times
from scalar or on your own not yet no worries okay my initial round any
specific feedback you got it okay got it oh depending on your prior experience
that was affecting okay great so guys do let me know I'll share my screen if it's
visible we have lot to cover today can you see the screen share like it's
working fine great cool let me open just a second
you can also see the iPad being here right iPad is visible right say there
are no disturbances right my fan is running at speed so just want to check
with you guys like do you hear the noise no noise right great so today guys will
end most of the project complete most of the you know all the features but will
be will be left with I believe local storage and functionalities because
we'll discuss some theory part on that and then we'll implement it but other
than that we'll complete mostly we'll wait for another minute or two let me
start three minutes timer then we'll get started meanwhile if anyone want to talk
about anything they want to share anything please
can you try to fill the whole text area once then create a ticket okay let's do
that there is nothing like filling whole text area some bit because text race can
be expandable by default we change the CSS part of it so let's see this
okay let's have keep on pressing Q see I can keep on getting the scroll but
let's say if I do and do this okay the wrap is missing is it flex wrap let's
see this
but this is on this will apply only on parent let's see this
I'll choose display as flex then let's say flex direction column then flex wrap
okay it is touching all the way
give me a second
wait this long that's fine but if you want to wrap the text area the text
content text wrapped let's say text wrap
nothing works
let's see I'm applying on just a second we'll check that on we'll check that on
some with we'll check on that and we'll see fix this one okay word wrap break
okay
okay fine yeah this works so let me add this word wrap the text area
so it's working like normal rap but let me refresh and check this
still it doesn't work let me give it to the parent element itself
okay yeah there's lot to learn guys thanks Sashank okay I think is can we
get started with today's class second someone ping in once in whatsapp group
we are on time I don't want to get delayed today we have too many topics to
cover okay let's drop you know can drop a position whatsapp group meanwhile I'll
start writing things down yeah I think I received a message thank you guys so we
started with Kanban board project and we started with understanding
requirements then we discussed wireframe then we went on with development when we
started at work we completed HTML and most of the CSS part in first class then
in recent class we completed you know ticket creation
right ticket removal right these two features isn't it guys we have
completed till now so like I hope this till now whatever we have discussed on
the logic point of is those points are clear right I have you know added one
sort of logic like using event bubbling how many of you understand event
bubbling concept clearly give it up so if you understand even bubbling I see one
thumbs up one thumbs down I see two three okay good amount of people who
understand it there's some other people who don't understand so one thing I'll
do here is that I'll pick it up in the last point guys because the way I'll
write the code would be different so I'll pick it up at last I'll try to go
with the flow then I'll teach that concept and then I'll explain this code
how this works that would be fine right because we'll add will work on
implementing those features like remaining features then guys can you
share whatsapp group link so one thing I'll do is that I'll create a new
script script one dot JS inside that I'll repaste this whole logic we can
implement most of the things using event bubbling concept too but I'll try to
teach the other way around then we can explore like how can you improve the
existing logic okay let's say I keep this function as it is and let's say okay
fine but repeating again the whole thing what we have done till now is that
you know we discussed two things mainly one was like creating a ticket like if
you see create ticket function where we were calling this on click of you know
I'll function alt button and you can see here like this one whenever you are
clicking like on a model whenever you're clicking alt we were actually creating a
ticket we're passing text area value then we're creating a ticket and then we
were resetting all the things like resetting the text area changing the
design of model and cleaning up all color section and everything right so
once we did this then we explored like how can we handle remove to handle
remove first we know that we have to switch on that cross button which will
allow you to delete it so for that we added one event listener on remove
button where only if this flag is true then we were throwing alert delete
button has activated and we made it color as red then once it is only
activated we were checking a condition condition and handle remove like only if
it is hand remove task flag is true then we were removing the ticket so I hope
everyone everyone's power like point is clear till now what we have discussed in
earlier class is anyone having any doubt from the code perspective other than
the same and bubbling concept so I hope this all points are clear so I'll put
down the agenda like what we will be covering today okay so we may not be
able to complete whole project today a few parts will be left so but I'll tell
you what what are my plans to complete okay so since creation and deletion were
done now comes the edit part now the edit part specifically using lock
button like clicking on lock and changing things then once this is done
then filter changing status of ticket by clicking header like the stage in
which ticket is then filtering the tickets by color status so these are the
three things that I want to cover but there will be another thing is that I
will talk about the feature like on click off double click on color filter
color render all tickets so this is one extra feature that I want to add it but
these are the least of the things that we will be working on in a way
like all the features will be implemented today but we'll talk about
the persistence layer next class where we'll talk about like local storage
concept because I have to introduce I have to talk on what's on a theory part
I'm trying to move it to the next class where will be fresh will be completing
all features will make some necessary changes and then we'll go ahead is that
clear guys is agenda clear what will be doing it today great now let's let's
let's get started with today's classes I hope you will be supporting me like as
you did it in last class with your you know suggestions doubts you know all the
things that you are thinking from a problem statement now if you see the
place where we stopped in last class was let's say I'm creating a task one and
I'm creating a ticket now now comes a point where if I want to edit this task
I have to click on this lock button isn't it so once I click a lock button I
should be able to edit this task now let's just think if I am clicking here
so what what should be the point of you know how we should approach it like how
should we approach it like what could be the first thing that comes to your mind
do you want to add an event listener if you want to add an event listener to
which thing you want to add a listener and how you want to do it set the lock
add listener change flag flag to make text editable okay great those are the
steps right is everyone agreeing with what somebody tripati has suggested
simple and straightforward right let's let's do these things let's do these
things simple and straightforward steps okay so first first and foremost thing
let me go back here now if you see I have like handle remove function same
logic I'll I'll try to say that I'll create a function called let's say I
create a function called handle lock on this lock I have to listen to some event
listener now that event listener is always present on a ticket let's say I
have receiving the ticket each ticket now on this ticket adding a event
listener but for all the ticket we don't need to add it since it's we are
similarly pointing out the specifically to this but this icon let's let's go and
trim it down and reach this icon out of this ticket if you see in HTML part let
me split this not the HTML part we don't need it because we have code on
the top no if you see here the ticket specifically this whole container right
whole ticket is something we have to reach out something like class of lock
once we reach this class lock then we have to go inside the children element
which is icon okay let's try to do that firstly what I'll do it is that let's
say I I say that const let's say ticket lock element I say the query selector
document dot query selector inside that I'll pass like last lock so what I'm
trying to do it here is that I'm trying to reach that lock now inside this lock
I have to get exact element like ticket lock icon let's say I'm reaching out
that particular icon ticket lock element dot children of 0th element okay so if
you see first I restart this lock class inside that I went out to the children
to get me this thing now on this one's once what I'll do it on this one is
that I'll select this lock icon and I'm adding an event listener hey if you if
someone is clicking this thing I have to do something right simple so on
clicking of this thing what we are doing is some is some like let's say if you go
back and see right there should be an identifier from the design perspective
let's say there's a ticket some random ticket once I click this I should be
able to identify that hey someone had made a content editable so what I'm
thinking here is that let's change the icon once a user clicks it let's show
that like lock is open like going back to the font awesome site let's let's go
back to the font awesome for now some then I go to the icons let's say if you
see lock I said that lock open let's search this if you see this thing so
we'll be using this one and we'll try to toggle it now toggling that lock open
and close same functionality let's take this so what we'll do is that I'll copy
this open because if you see I just need FA lock open class because for the both
the classes if you go and see on the top if a lock if a solid is common thing if
a lock open and if a lock is a something which I have to toggle I have to remove
this class and add open class that's just just those two things I have to
handle so what I'll do here is that let's say I have two classes lock ticket
saying that I have to use this one I'll use this and then I'll say that unlock
ticket okay so just I'm using those same lock open not unlock so here the first
use case that I'll do is like once a user is clicking this one right I'll check
firstly which type of icon is existing in this like if particular ticket a lock
icon is having let's say class list inside this class list contains what I'll
check is that if it is already this is containing if it is a lock already
let's say if there's a lock already then I'm supposed to unlock it so what I'll
do is that hey I'll say that ticket list out of this ticket you know element dot
class list dot remove if a lock and then add if a lock open is this idea clear to
you guys like what I'm trying to do I'm just like toggling it using those icons
like I'm just using CSS classes I'm just using them okay same thing I'll do it
here so I'll put this on top then I'll click remove then I'll add it let's see
this if this is working fine script is something we are editing now going back
to our code let's say I have this random information of text and then we create a
ticket now once I'm clicking this nothing is happening let's see this why
this is not happening okay we haven't even called this function yet now handle
ticket needs a ticket now if you want to add a listener to a particular locks of
it all the tickets right we can only you know add a listener as we have discussed
in last class only from a place where we are actually creating a ticket because
here we'll have access to the ticket which is being created some hand just
where how the the way we handled removing will also handle the same way
the locking system okay let's go back and try to see if this is working fine
some random text and I click all now if I click this see there's something
happening here let's see this what's happening so if you see okay so we were
actually adding you know lock removing lock to the parent element instead we
should have been doing it for lock icon right now let's try to recreate some
alpha gibberish art now when I click this so yes how many of you did
understand this logic if there is someone who didn't understand they can
very well give me thumbs down so that I can repeat it because I moved a bit fast
here reason behind it's the same logic that we have still now implemented okay
so repeating it again guys no now let's see what's actually happening here okay
let's say okay I'll update here ticket no so let's see this case firstly my idea
was to you know play around with something called as lock as I have this
ticket no I have to add an event listener to this lock no there can be a
number of tickets and number of tasks which will have a number of locks so for
each task you will have a locks one one lock so for a way if I can if I want to
add a listener to this particular lock the only way that I can deal with it is
that whenever I'm creating this ticket itself I'll add a listener to that
particular thing so I called a function from create ticket itself and inside
that handle lock I passed on the ticket which is created if you see after
appending to the main container and passing on that ticket itself into the
handle lock inside handle lock I'm just trying to attach to that particular icon
that lock icon and event listener click and this part of code will be only
executed only when user clicks on that particular lock icon so now once user is
clicking on this so we are checking what type of is it a locked icon is present
or it's a locked icon so if I see if you see if it is a lock already it's like a
fail lock because that that's how we are talking CSS classes checking from font
awesome so if it is a fail lock then if it is a fail lock then I'm trying to
remove that class and then I'm adding a fail lock open open the lock and if not
if it is already open then I'm removing the open and adding a lock to it so just
toggling this icon adding an event listener to this icon just added a
listener and I toggled it depending on a condition depending on which type of
icon is there is this clear guys now
any doubts anyone having any doubts okay great now now comes interesting thing
now comes the main tricky thing like once you open the lock we have to make
this editable does anyone know how can they edit any content on any website
any content on any website there's a one powerful attribute which allows you to
change anything like even yeah I think Hemangi has suggested let's say if I
want to if I want to change the start even if I want to change the start I can
do this very well like if you see there is an attribute called like if I add
something like let's say content editable okay to true no once I do this
okay it restart refresh let's say we are editing this font or some site it's one
tag and I add something like let's say
content editable I pass on value like true okay once I make this country
now as soon as I click here I can write my name on actual website which won't be
saved anyways which will be you know dynamic in nature but on the click of
alt if you remember on ticket you are always updating that content right as
for our application logic but do you understand the power of content a double
attribute on any content like across any system like you can go to the
scaler site also let's say if we go for scaler.com for me invented dashboard
will load I don't know what this is there are too many things okay let's let it be
but content editable allows you to do anything guys anything that you want to
deal with okay that's our basic idea so what I'll do is that firstly when lock
is open I'll get an access to this content then I'll make it content data
blast true so that user can edit that content let's let's try to do that first
you for if you want to make any change to this one we have to get access to
this particular text so in order to do that if you see here we already have a
ticket right we already have a ticket now using the ticket we can always get
an access to this task area where we are having whole info of a particular
ticket okay so let's go there let's come back here I say that const ticket task
area while ticket dot query selector inside that I'll say that task area get
me that ask once I have this ticket task area I have to just in order to deal
with attributes what is the one method that we have discussed on any of the
elements how can you add a new attribute from JS just think of it like we have
discussed this already and I believe we have used it here somewhere yeah like
this one right if you see we were adding class set attribute right like
earlier we were adding a set attribute to add a new class this was an attribute
so same way if you want to add an attribute to existing element HTML
element I'll use that same thing when when there is an unlock when a user is
trying to unlock I'll make ticket task area dot set attribute I'll add a new
attribute card content editable and I'll make it as true and when user is
trying to lock a ticket I'll make it as false okay now let's see this if it is
working as we expected so let's create a task some gibberish and let's say I
have this one once I click this there's nothing this you see editable things
are editable now I can go and say this is the task one and I can click back to
close that like close the lock again is this clear guys how this locking
mechanism is working pretty simple and straightforward compared to what we
have done yesterday isn't it just getting an adding an event listener to
this lock and clicking on unlock we'll make it this country table and once you
user edit shirts again he clicks back on this one we are locking that so simple
straightforward if else condition and nothing much more interesting here
isn't it so any doubts guys on this handle lock how we are dealing with
handle lock
clear right great now now comes the second thing that we have to deal with
is that let's say I create a task one no I click here no do you remember we
earlier thought that you know this is a like pink statement pink line pink
color starts that you know tasks which need to be done when we say green it is
it means to be say that in progress and when we say sorry when we say blue it is
completed sorry to it need to be evaluated and when we say black task is
completed so these are the four statuses earlier we discussed now let's say if I
want to make it this task into in progress one click of this thing I this
color palette I'll be I should be able to make this color palette color change to
the green on the next time if I click again I should be able to make it to the
blue then I should be able to make it to black right this is the thing that we
should be able to play around with now I want you guys to think like how would
you handle this requirement let's say this comes to you now it would be
pretty straightforward that hey I'll get an access I'll get an access to this one
each ticket again same I will add a listener to this one but how would you
know that on click of this particular color I have to what color next color
would come and how would you update this color just think of that one how would
you update the color meanwhile I'll try to set up the dummy logic or you can say
the usual logic that we do it okay what I'll do is that let's say I say simple
handle color again because adding event listener is same thing let's say I go
back here I say that handle color hey I'm receiving a ticket in this inside
this then what I'll do supposed the same thing that I'll add let's say let's say
once once I have to get an access to this color from ticket dot query
selector
now if you go back and see what however adding earlier color was this one using
something called a stick at color isn't it so let's let's pick this one
okay no this is fine you got a access to this color now what's next or else
let's say this is as a color if I have to give a right naming convention color
band on this color band now you have to one thing you have to do is like add a
listener to this one so let's say I also add a listener to this one color band
odd add event listener and something that we are listening to is a click type
now once we click something we have to do some logic now tell me something like
what you want to do or else give me the statement so that I can write the
statement what could be the idea let's say I am trying to write a comments
here what would you want to do it here let's say user comes and clicks on that
color pallet some gibberish no we have a listener attached to this one now when
a user clicks we should be able to identify what could be the next color
using the current color isn't it
now how can we do that
how can we do that loop a loop on what some bit a loop on what where would you
apply a loop on so can you guys think this way that on classes of color but
you need a classes of color first on something like an array right once you
have this let's say const color and then you can add a color to it and then you
const colors once you have this colors let's say if you see what order we have
this is light pink light green blue and black let's say I make those colors
itself light pink let's say light green
then light blue then black so using this array if if you think if you say
this if we if I have this array now if you see what if if the current color is
pink I'm supposed to update that color with light green which is like index
plus one right that's the same logic we can apply like if the current color is
light green then we can make light blue if it is light blue then I can make
black and someone clicking black I can make light pink again so we have to just
keep on moving on a circular motion of the same array right identifying current
and selecting the next index of it guys are you able to think in this way like
is anyone facing challenge understanding my point here if you are not able to
understand give me thumbs down guys feel free to do that thing okay great great
at least one to further guys okay circular movement got it but not getting
any logic how to do it okay but but let's let's let's do this once if we
write first let's we write down in the comments part like like just a comment
we have to find we have to find color of the band okay just existing color of the
and then index of that color from colors array and then we need to update color
of a band with next index of color is this is what we have to do this one
right is this point clear to everyone now what we are supposed to do it as I
see some of the comments those great guys the region summit but is is this
point everyone able to understand it give me thumbs down if stills there is
someone who is struggling to understand the point like how we can handle color
band logic someone picks a random color how he would pick it up enough even if
I let's say week like let's say I clear task one even if we pick green doesn't
matter we'll try to find out the index of this green then we are supposed to
move to blue when we use the clicks here so it's just a moving things in order
when we are changing the color palette it is like status right if you remember
what we have pointed this one as
pink was to be done now then we have green in progress then blue to be
validated black was completed when user is toggling on a bar right when a user
is toggling on this bar he's supposed to move in this order itself
then black to green ok black to green this is in a circular motion right once
if it goes into the black then you'll go to pink then you can update to green
this will happen in circular motion we can reopen the ticket all the times we
can update the status of ticket again I think few people have already added the
handle the edge cases already if you see the above suggestion people have
suggested but coming back to that I'll show it like how we can do it now let's
say first and foremost thing first and foremost thing we have to find a color
of the band now how we can find the color of the band firstly let's say once
I have this ticket color if you see this ticket color this is the ticket color
right if I get if I get let's say const current color equal to color band dot
class list of 0th element let's do console dot log if I'm able to get
current color okay let's see if I'm able to get the current color now some
gibberish let's say firstly if I go and see this if I click here I'm able to get
that light pink axis is this point clear to everyone firstly I'll come back to
Abhinav's question somebody thank you for taking this but how I'm able to
access this light pink is clear now how I would be able to find the index of
this light pink is the question now let's say I say that current color index
do you see this I got this autocomplete but let's say I can write this one in two
ways index of I can use it also I can use something like another way of
writing is find index whereas it will be using as a iterator each time a color
comes I'll return color equal to current color so this is the one way you can
write down then the other way around was like simple current color index like
console dot log current color index okay let's see if this is working fine
create a some gibberish task and selecting and doing it now once I click
index of let's see
no
hmm I did he's in right winner okay let's see if this logic is working fine
I uncommon this logic and I'll remove this one as of now just let's let's
just verify I didn't apply it on array pardon me guys thank you once I click
this I'm able to access light green is of index one okay so hope this part is
clear now the second and third most thing is like finding the next index
okay so if I say const new color index or new color let's say if I directly
update it if I directly new color let's say if I give this as you can say
colors of current color index plus one and once I have this current color plus
index now the the thing I have to toggle is I have to do only from the classes
remove and add now I will do that remove and add on the color band now once I
have this class list I can do remove the current color and color band dot class
list dot add new color is this logic clear to everyone like how we are
writing this one does anyone face any challenge here there's a one condition
I'm missing but there's already few people answered that one for circular
array let's say if you see this is the same thing that we have done first we
have to find the color of the band now if you see for first sentence I found
the current color of the band then index of that color okay I found the current
index of that color okay then we need to update the color of the band with the
next index color so first I got the next color which is our next index color new
color then I removed it the existing one added the new color right plain simple
steps now if you go and see let's create one task
then I click option then if I toggle this if you see I'm going to green now
yeah coming back to that question okay no did I make no let's see what we just
did it let's try to delete this existing one let's recreate a new one again to
just to show you the behavior okay we have this now going back into this part
of logic what's happening when I click on pink now if you see the current color
would be the light pink now once I get the index of light pink now let's see
what is the index of light pink if you see the guard index value is 0 now if
you go to the next thing now second new color becomes light green since index
one value was a light green if you see it from the air itself then we are
removing current color and adding new color okay so green it has become green
now from green let's if I click it again now I click play again if you see I got
current index as a minus 1 what could be the issue what could be the issue just
think of this firstly what happened here if someone think can think what
problem just we arrived at oh well create the rest I missed did anyone can
think of this thing what just happened can anyone look at this what just
happened here ticket color once we adding new color right if you see in the
logic we are removing existing color and adding new color whenever new color is
added using you know this one class list add all the colors which are new colors
coming it will be added in the second question or the last question right like
first earlier if we remove light pink which was in the first position then we
added light green light green went on the second portion now we are trying to
remove the ticket color which is at zero at the index because we try to fetch it
existing current color from zero at the index now the code is breaking at this
line is this point clear like is an everyone able to think from this point
anyone who don't understand this one is anyone who don't understand this one
guys if there is anyone who don't understand this point give me thumbs
down if there is anyone okay now if everyone is understanding this point now
suggest me how can you address this issue how can you add okay I've been
says one more time now let's let's walk through this one again let's walk
through this one again okay let's refresh this one I'll create a new ticket
some random gibberish no just look at this I've you know what happened here
firstly on clicking off if you currently see right if you see if I go into this
current ticket that got created in the ticket container if you see I'm having
light pink and ticket color as a this banner for this one okay now once I go
into source code if you once I click here if you see I'm getting access to
this light pink from the dom token list because I'm trying to access 0th
element inside the class list okay now once I try to get an access to the 0th
element I am able to fetch exactly the light pink one that point is clear no
because it's right thing is at 0th question once I do enter if you see
current color is something that we wanted now using this one light pink we
were figuring out what would be the next color that we have to update with light
green so once we did it now if I'm removing it let's say if I go into the
next step of removing it now if you see we are removing this light pink as soon
as I click a play as soon as I click a play in the source tab or here in the
limits tab just think look at it here light pink will be removed light pink is
removed now next color will be added which is light green light green is
added in the second question now when I try when I try to do it again from green
to blue when I'm trying to access the 0th index of color band I'm getting an
access to ticket color instead of light green that was a bug is that point
clear everyone I try to repeat and show that whole debugging part so I have to
address this issue instead of going and addressing you know like changing the
position of how we are adding it can we think of addressing this issue in the
right way here itself in the function rather than trying to access current
color this way
think of it simply now can we say this class list is array of elements can we
say this class list is an array of elements once we try to access ticket
color light green light blue any number of elements you add once I get an access
to this element then I can say that class list and I have to select other
than ticket color is my current color other than ticket color whatever color
is there present in this day is the color that I want to is a current color
or that bad is anyone able to think in that perspective just I'm trying to say
that simple example let's say what I'll do that I'll say that let current color
okay now I can say out of this color band class list dot for each I'll get
color okay I'll say the return
color not equal to dot to get color
is anyone able to think this way this would work or it wouldn't work let's say
I make it const here itself instead of writing it later in this step did like
is it clicking guys are you able to understand this point like I'm just
iterating to the existing color and I'm checking that if the current color is not
equal to ticket color give me that because I have only two things here I
have only two things there one is the color of the band other is the ticket
color so I'm saying that other than ticket color give me anything that you
have let's see this if this logic is working firstly let's see this if this
logic is working I'll say this is a task one I click shift for the old key now
once I have this let's say click this now I go to the next step now let's say
what I'm getting here okay I'm getting undefined let's say I write down the
logic here itself colors dot class list of zero at index so it's a colors band
dot class list dot for each right I'm getting color inside that if I try to
return the statement color not equal to something like ticket color okay I have
to check this one whether I'm getting something like ticket color or dot
ticket color can we just unshift and start always huh right some with we
are iterating through this one I'm just picking the other color we can do
unshift also but let's do that both things some bit okay whatever you are
suggesting let me just go through this one that's I think this one I go inside
this I say color I'm getting light pink so I'm supposedly not sure I should
picking a dot one dot operator sorry darn I have to remove this so let's say
I readdress this one option then I click here no I can pick this still
just a second guys I went on to the color then if it is not equal to this
one then it should return it why I'm getting here inside this again okay now
I am in the light pink no ticket color let's make double equal to strictly
checking is anyone able to think why this logic is failing I'm just going
going on a color band I have two things have 0th index sorry for each will
always go for all the elements doesn't matter the the way I'm writing that
condition was wrong okay the way I was writing that condition was wrong so
pardon me guys no one thing I can always do is let's say current color the myth
the logic I was using was wrong so let's say I have a for loop simple for loop
instead of this one let's say I use
and I can say that if it's not double equal to ticket color then the current
color would be this one okay let's see this
still I got something an issue okay color color band I'm making too many
mistakes today again again a color color band here again here three times now
it's working fine no but but if you guys see this the one way is like trying
to I treating through a loop and finding the other way around but the one
suggestion that I've got from some bit was Rick can't we always try to add new
color into the first element no we could have done that we could have done that
some bit easily but only if class list class list exactly works like array if
we can apply all the properties that we can apply on the like array here you
cannot add it like if you can do it see if you remember the array we cannot do
we can do push and pop but we cannot do add and remove okay some with reparties
that point here like why I was trying to through I truth to the loop and find it
out no firstly I'll try to explain this kind of thing that what I was trying to
do here is that if you see let's say we are a green in color now if I click on a
green so I'm going through the list of color bands now if you see on the color
bank last list I have two colors ticket color and light green light green so I'm
checking like if the existing in the loop right in the color color the class
list if the current color is not equal to ticket color get then the current
color would be the this one the other thing right if you see inside if I go I
cannot go inside the if condition because it was pointing to the ticket
color now comes the index one index one now if you see in this index one is
light green and this condition will satisfy it will go inside that and
update the current color as light green now if you find that current color is
light green same we've tried to find the index of it then move to the next index
and then remove and add so I hope this point is clear a basic point I made
many mistakes while writing it because too many autocorrects and too many
things guys does anyone need a dry run on this because I feel it's clear cut
what if last index coming to that point now what if last index now if I if I go
on a last index and minus one I do plus one and I try to access out of the
colors one sort of error we supposedly we have we should be getting it what
should be that error if you are trying to access nth element of an array
index out of bond right now how can you address that issue how can you address
that issue if you don't want to go into index out of bond and then you can want
to rotate it yeah same thing you have to you know get the reminder using color
start length simply right now let's see this let's try to create a task task one
and I select pink color and option now if I want to move to the next status
green I can move from green to blue I can go from blue to black I can go and
from black again I can go to pink then to green then to blue then to black
again okay and the second feature that we implemented was this one like
updating layer task two and then I can close back again again I can update the
status so is this both things guys clear to you what we had just done like
simply selecting from the current array of the like I'm trying to find the next
element and just updating that dude if you see even in the handle lock if I go
to the handle lock method here also we were doing the same thing remove and add
logic here also we are doing that same removal add logic but we were figuring
out what to remove what to add
should be working only when it is unlocked right not exactly you can know
the status status can be moved only the content need to be updated when you have
to you know update it this lock is for only making edit the content not for the
status status can be moved anyways okay guys is there anyone who don't
understand this yet like is there anyone finding challenge understanding these
two functionalities that we have built yeah if you want we can change
accordingly yeah we can do that even if you want to do it on unlock you can
also do that just you have to add it in the above method guys do you want me to
reiterate both the functionalities or this point is clear like how we are
approaching this both things
because it's pretty straightforward simple you know trying to get an access
of the element figuring out like what to remove what to add and just the logic
that we have to apply is like on this array for this changing the status of
the color okay so now what what is the feature that left guy to left to build
what is the feature that one last feature which is left to build filter
right now think from let's let's try to create multiple tasks as of now let's
create multiple tasks
I'm creating some gibberish tasks now on click of pink we should be able to only
say pink on click of green we should be able to do decreasing green on click of
blue we should be able to see only this particular on click of this anything
filters that's what the functionality we were trying to build it now get the
class from filter get the class from the ticket if matches display block else
none straightforward simple thing that some it says but if I make it display
none you know play around with that just let's see this okay what I will do
is that I'll select this whole ticket one thing I want to straightforwardly
say is that let's say if I go on ticket container now ticket container doesn't
have any separate identification how would you make it a one particular ticket
as a display none and other thing as a display block or display flex anything
and unless you don't have right identifier so if you make ticket
container index now how would you access this index main ticket container dot
children you want to do it that way okay but think of other way around think of
other way around any other approaches is anyone having any other approaches any
other approaches some with can you think of this way like firstly as you
suggested we can get all the children all the tickets and we can filter by
what color is there and we can once you filter it can you render the whatever
filtered array output is there just like what I mean to say is that let's say
what's my idea is let's say you have ticket one two three what else let's say
pink pink green black let's say you have this four tickets all are these tickets
inside the main ticket container once user clicks on any of the filter let's
on this is pink this is let's say green this is blue this is let's say black let's
say once user clicks on pink it click this one can I get an access of this
array and I'll say that filter me of this array and give me output which only
matching this color that's I say that I'll get I'll apply all the all the
tickets whichever tickets are there with me on green and black filter it which is
matching the current color which is clicked like pink if it is only equal to
pink or let's say color color then return me into the new array and new
array will be only two things right out of this thing I'll get only two tickets
pink and pink and once I get this I can remove all the tickets I can add back
all these tickets filtered one is anyone able to is everyone able to
understand this idea like what I'm just suggest trying to explain just
filtering out depending on user click and whatever filtered output is there
will render that one and will remove everything okay let me write down in the
comments part so that you will be able to understand this firstly first and
foremost thing before going to that part itself let's say I try to go and get the
access to ticket okay no first and foremost thing is like I have main
ticket container isn't it firstly I'll get an access to this tool bar and the
toolbar if you remember if you see here that toolbar is this toolbox container
okay inside this toolbar container we have toolbox priority container we'll
get an access to this one let's say I go and select const toolbox color document
dot query selector inside this I'll say this class get me toolbox priority
container or else one other way around other way around is if you see all the
things having common color color property which will give us all the four
colors whichever is user is having access to if we are going by this thing
we have to again check or using the event bubbling process because we are
applying on a parent element currently we won't pick it do it that way so I'm
going to back check is checking color and instead of query selector I'll use
query selector on okay so once I have access to all the colors now the second
next thing I would do is let's say this is a plural form I'll iterate through
this all the colors
okay once I have all the colors for all the this toolbox colors we have to add
event list so just let me add this event list to this colors okay toolbox colors
dot I dot add event listener on each of event listener we are listening to
something called as click click event then we'll write down our logic here
but this part this four five lines of code is this clear what I'm trying to do
I'm just trying to get an access to those four colors and I'm adding a
listener click to it I think this is something we have been doing for each
and every piece of project like every item that we're adding a listener and
we're listening to click or any other event no inside this event now once
clicked once anything is clicked we have to access its particular color now how
we can access the color if you go back and see in the HTML again here the color
is index 0 right of toolbox so same logic again we'll use class list of 0
let's say I say const selected color selected tool let's say selected toolbox
color some selected toolbox color I would say toolbox dot class list of 0th
element let's see if I do this if I'm able to get the thing that we want okay
I go back into the console I try to click pink I'm able to get the pink if I
clicks this one light green I'm getting light blue I'm also good light black
black also getting that okay right so now comes the main point we got the color
now we have to filter based on all the existing tickets now how we would be
able to get the tickets now yeah how we will be able to get the tickets let's
say even if you try to get let's say main ticket container if we even if you
go through main ticket container inside that you will have all the children
elements and everything is fine but if let's say if we can store all the
tickets that are getting created somewhere what if we can store somewhere
all the tickets are getting created like an array because I can store all the
objects right whatever objects any type of objects it can store right is anyone
able to think like let's say what I'm saying is that that's how I say that
const tickets array I say this is an empty array right inside this ticket
array what I'll do it here is that I'll go to ticket create ticket now whenever
user is creating a ticket whenever user is creating a ticket I'll also push an
item into this an array okay and what information I'll push it here is that
firstly if you see here what are the elements that we are building it now
let's say I make it here as ticket ID I'll cut it here I'll paste it here and
I'll say that get me the ticket ID so firstly let's say I build an object I
say this is as a ticket ID okay fine then we are also passing something as a
ticket info okay then also we are pushing something called as ticket
status right let's say model priority color isn't it if we are able to store
this data of whatever all the tickets that we are pushing it it would be
easier to filter this array and do it no it would be easy to filter and store the
existing tickets also like if you in case if you want to reset it let's say
if you want to reset it if you filter the main container and remove and you
know you remove that like let's say you have a four tickets and you click the
pink ticket which is only one status and you remove all other things where you
will get back from so I'm trying to store in a extra memory space such that
we can if user if user do something like reset we would be able to show all the
other tickets also like if user doesn't want to apply filter again like applying
filter and remove the filter is everyone able to get the intuition that I'm
trying to build here guys are you able to get my point or I'm running bit speed
today like I just want to know I see only two thumbs up guys there are good
amount of people I just want to recheck like or you want to take the break and
come back and then build this one okay everything is going over my head because
joining I'll try to repeat this and get like okay people says break okay what
I'll do is that let's say I'll give ten minutes break okay and I'll try to I'll
try to repeat whole thing whatever we have done in this ten minutes break okay
so that everyone can understand then we can follow up on that is that clear
whoever want to take break they can freely take that break whether this idea
works because some people facing challenge understanding so I want to
repeat the whole things that we have this let's say I say this is as edit
content and change status
get push okay okay so Abhinav says that
yes please let me know if you want a break and then repeat it or you want me
to repeat then like how you want me to do it like you let's give me thumbs up
if you want me to explain during break give me thumbs down if you want me to
repeat everything or after break okay cool so one thing we'll do is like we'll
take five minutes break and come back understand everything what we have done
today once we get complete confidence then we'll move ahead okay we'll do that
okay let's take five minutes break guys and come back and then we'll move it
ahead okay I'm starting the break guys please refresh yourself and come back
I'll try to repeat it and we'll get a complete understanding of it
you
Guys is everyone back and am I audible right no can we get started I will try to repeat
it what we have done till now then we will move ahead okay no let's go back to the first
thing what we have done so today we started with something called as handling the locking
mechanism now if you see if you want to handle a lock to anything any task right now while
creating a ticket post creating a ticket once you click all or shift anything only then you
will be able to get access to that lock right now for each ticket you create let's say create a
task to now for each ticket there will be a separate lock identifier and for each lock
you have to add a listener to it now in order to do this what I was doing here is that once
ticket has been created and appended I'm using this ticket container and adding a listener to
it inside this handle lock if you go inside this handle lock to open this if you see first thing
what I'm doing is that I'm going to get the access to that lock from that HD dom then I'm
trying to get the access to that icon inside the dom if you see in HD in here when we created a
ticket we have the icon is present inside this so first I was getting access to this one this
then I'm going inside that as a children's first element okay once I got an access to that then
I was toggling two CSS classes in font awesome if we mean to say that if a particular icon is having
a fail lock it means to say that it will look like this as a lock icon and if you use apply a CSS
like a fail lock open class to a particular icon then it will look like a lock which is open so
I was toggling this lock checking the condition what is the current icon if it is lock then I'm
trying to open that lock if it is already open then I'm trying to lock that particular ticket
so I was toggling between remove and add and simultaneously I was using some you know on the
ticket task area like whatever task it is once you click unlock you're supposed to make this
content editable so in order to make this content editable I was using one of the attribute called
content editable which can make any content and any website in the table so it's getting
access to this ticket area and I was adding this attribute once if I pass our boolean value true
that becomes editable and if I want to make it not editable I can make as a false is this
guy is handle lock clear to everyone how the handle lock is working anyone having any doubt
still does anyone want me to repeat handle lock cool I on this I think you understood
handle lock clearly now now comes the second thing which is handling the color of a ticket
now if you see the ticket status color can revolve around only four things right if you
remember our first class even when we discuss requirements it can revolve around this four
things which is pink and green then blue then black all these four colors and it will be the
same sequence order also because status it can start from to be done in progress to be
validated then complete it status now if I if we follow the same order then what I was what
our idea was hey can we make something like an array of elements because if current color is
green then we have to make it blue if it is blue then we have to make it black if it is black I
have to make it pink that was a basic idea but in order to do this firstly for each and every
ticket again I have to get access to this one this particular color palette so again while
creating ticket itself I passed on this ticket inside this handle color now once we come to this
handle color if you see I try to get access to this ticket color and I add event listener to
inside this color band now since while adding the next color or previous color any color the
position where the particular color was getting added was like moving here and there like since
if you see whenever we are adding inside this class list right always a new color will be added
or the last position okay that's how this class list not add whether it works but here when you
go and see how the way we have designed it is that model priority color comes first position then
we gave ticket color now we are trying to remove this whatever existing color is there then we are
adding new color which is supposed to be coming next to the ticket color so for handling that
edge case what we have done is we have went through the existing colors whichever existing
colors are there here I mean existing CSS classes okay if you see this if you go to any of the
ticket so see we have two CSS classes we were going through all the existing CSS classes of
that particular thing and we were selecting current color as a color which is not equal to
ticket color it is having two colors only if something which is not ticket color is light pink
so we say that a current color is light pink and once we get that light pink color in the
current color then I was checking index of the light pink hey inside this colors array once I
get it a 0th index then I'll make an index plus one out of that colors array give me that light
green color inside a new color remove the current color which is pink color add the green color
and this percentage like you know this thing is to handle the edge case of rotational issue
whenever you go to the endpoint end of the n minus 1th array of element in order to handle
index out of bond issue we were using this percentage symbol I mean percentage and colors
which will always give you the reminder in that size of the array I hope this logic is clear how
handle color is working guys if even if there is a someone who don't understand it I'm okay with
it I will try to re-explain them show them debugging it's okay no no worries I see one
thumbs down cool anyone else who didn't understand it Ankit Tiwari says he didn't
understand it Ankit can I take take your doubt and doubt session possibly if it is possible
okay cool so other than Ankit I think everyone have understood so I'll explain Ankit again
now comes the third thing third the main thing which is like filtering all the existing tickets
now the idea was in order to filter all existing tickets firstly we'll get an access to this four
elements in order to again get this access to this elements if you see here there is a one common
property across these elements is like color like CSS so what I did here is I did query selector
on give me the all the colors I I treated through color and attached an event listener to it cool
all things are fine we attached event listeners here now now comes the main logic like how we
will filter it so the point where we got stuck is now if I say let's say document dot query selector
okay inside this if I say main let me copy this completely
let's and I put it in strings let's say I am trying to get an access to this one now and I say
the children okay when I do this children I am getting this two HTML elements two tickets okay
depending on what color this select we can always get inside this element and we can check again
filter it by their color and filter it down that's that's all doable that's all doable but
what if like let's say if I filter it down and I only read under the screen with only the colors
let's say if I have also a task which is green in color let's say this is a task three which is
green in color okay now if we go by this approach what we were doing earlier like getting all the
access to this one let's say now I have three things now if user clicks pink and we filter
this existing Dom itself then I'll have only two tickets what if I want to see all the tickets
again because there's a one functionality which is left like if you see like something that I was
highlighting which I should be applying to cover it's like on click of like on double click let's
say on double click of filters
filter color render all the tickets
so we were saying that hey if you re-click once you once you clicked it filter it but once if
I double click on any of this one I want all the tickets now if you have filtered the Dom
already and stored only on the base of color if user again clicks double click where you will
get all the tickets from so that was my point okay so my idea was like what if I store what
if I store all the tickets that are being created an array and when I apply a filter on an array
because filter method like yeah on a filter once I filter it it will return me a new array right
and only I can render a new array once user clicks double-click it I can render whole ticket
array is this idea you are able to understand so once I have all the tickets in an array ticket
array once user double-click I can render all things whatever things are present inside this
if user clicks once I'll filter it based on the color of this array and render it that was an
idea now in order to store firstly all the tickets I went to ticket create ticket part
and I was trying to push all the things here now let's say instead of model priority color
where it is there let's say we store it here const I say this other ticket color
let's not do it this way no wherever this ticket color create ticket is being called
what I'll do is I'll tweak some things here that let's say we also pass model priority color from
here itself so that this becomes completely reusable also I'll say that an ID which is an
empty thing okay now I'll say firstly I am receiving ticket color then I'm getting ticket
info then I'm getting something called as ticket unique ID let's say I write unique ID okay now
if unique ID is present take that or else take short ID and taking ticket color I'll update it
here is this clear guys I didn't make any change I was just trying to you know pass it down to the
function call instead of directly getting it here okay I have done nothing new here so one
more thing I'll do is that here I'll make it as ticket color and I'll store it this model
priority color instead of this one let's say this one and I can make this as a const also
we can make this const guys is this clear what I was doing here like I'm why how I'm pushing
into this tickets array now I'll show you one thing before here I'll try to output all the
things that are happening inside this ticket array like how these things are being entered
in through this one let's see I go back I try to create some random task I create enter now
okay nothing got entered just a second
now when we are pushing it we have dynamic ID ticket info tickets color all things are
cool and let's say remove this handle lock also remove this
go to console if you see here inside the array two tickets got created I have two
tickets now the simple logic now would be to filter it now right once I have this ticket
array inside this ticket array I'm having all the tickets which are needed so if you see in
the class list of zero I'm having the color now if you see inside this array if I say like a few
let's say if I say this array dot let's say I say index one
let's say I try to get okay let's say let's come back here and when once we are I treating through
this one we'll get it now what I'm supposed to do here what could be the my idea here is like to
filter this one let's say I say that const filter tickets would be get all the tickets dot filter
and filter on basis of one condition now that condition would be hey on each ticket check
what you have to check if selected color toolbox is equal equal to ticket dot if you see the
that we are pushing it when we are creating a ticket was ticket color so whatever tickets
colors will be there matching that selected color I should be getting inside the this one
let's see this if this is working as expected okay no I'll also had filtered tickets as this
one then let's say I have here going back let me create few tickets no let's say I have green
color let's say I have again green color let's have some blue in color okay now I have four
things if you see if I expand it I have four tickets 0 1 2 3 4 and light green pink green
green blue if you say anything will be there here also now now if I select pink color now
let's say if I say pink color if you see filtered tickets inside that filter tickets I'm having
only one color which is this one so I'm filtering it now once user is clicking this I am supposed
to remove all the things and I add this one onto the screen is this clear guys what I what's my
approach is everyone able to follow up I don't see reactions okay I see one thumbs down no
worries I'll I'll show you back okay okay let's complete this and then I'll show you like what's
actually you know being done now first and foremost thing that I would do is let I equal
to zero instead of filtered colors I'm supposed to remove all the existing tickets from their
down okay so tickets array dot I dot remove but here if I want to remove all the tickets
just let me think how can I get access to all the tickets
okay huh one thing I can do always is that I can get all the all tickets access was using
document dot query selector all using all the tickets whichever are there now that
thing I can use ticket container this particular thing once I have access to this one I'm supposed
to remove all tickets of I dot remove so let's say I do this all tickets no now let's say if I
show you back to remove all tickets you can do parent element dot text content no text content
will remove the tick let's recheck the rest now I'm removing completely from Dom right I'm
selecting each ticket parent each alib ticket directly and I'm going to remove it let's see
that relation later parent and child I'll come back to that okay okay now once I remove this
all the tickets now I'm supposed to add back all the tickets now in order to add it what I'll do
is that I'll select filter tickets all the filter tickets and I'll say for each and let's say I
get each ticket I write a arrow function and I call something like create ticket inside this
I pass on all the properties that I need I say it needs ticket collector ticket color
so let's say I have a ticket dot ticket color then also ticket info then ticket dot ticket
ID once I do this it should be working fine but let's re verify if this is working some
gibberish pink if I click green let's say if I select pink it's working fine now if I select
I'm getting green again I'm getting two things now there is a bug okay I'll come to this bug
but let's let's refresh this one guys firstly I am trying to re-explain the approach that
followed here I'll try to write the comments so that you can follow up remove all the tickets
those are created and recreate the filtered tickets
okay get the color of the ticket get the selector color selected color of filter
okay then here filter the tickets based on selected color guys are you able to follow
up this four steps what I have done here firstly like first get the color which user has clicked
then filter all the tickets which are present in a ticket array once you have filtered one then I
am removing all the tickets firstly then whatever filtered is there I am trying to recreate using
create method create ticket okay now the only bug if you see the bug where I am getting here
let's say if I say let pink and I do this option if I click pink I get one ticket if I re-click
pink again I'm getting two times if I re-click I'll keep on getting the tickets now the reason
I'll tell you what happening is that when I'm trying to recreate using filtered right already
there is a one ticket added into this tickets array when we are pushing it so each time you
are trying to recreate it each you are pushing new elements into ticket array because ticket
array is being storing only one it should store only one time right multiple tickets are being
stored inside this one did anyone understand it like why this bug was coming like once you
created it you filtered it then again you are trying to recreate it this array is getting
duplicate tickets entered into this one multiple duplicate tickets are coming into this so in
order to address that one right in order to fix this one what I can say is that I'll use one
condition simple condition is that since when when first time when ticket you know when we
are creating first time ticket using plus icon we are not passing an ID we are passing an empty
string okay and when we are creating through this one filtered one we are actually passing
an ID which ticket need to be created so I can check on the length of the ticket ID if the
length is equal to zero only then push the element that's ticket ID dot length is less
than equal to zero only then push this element or else don't push into the array
no going back and retesting this one let's say I do this pink color I click option then I click
this one then let's say it's like green then again I click blue okay now I have three let's say I
click on blue I have only blue if I click on green I have only one if I click on red pink I
have this one only one now I am getting only one if I select black I don't have anything that's
fine this filter is working fine as of now but reexperiencing this one guys what what's what we
have done firstly I got an access to this buttons once I got an access what whatever user is clicking
I'm trying to get to know which is the user click button like he's clicking blue green or
pink using this statement I'm trying to get to understand which is selected to toolbox color
once I have this color I'm filtering all the tickets using array filter method simple weather
then I'm trying to remove all the tickets from the existing in the screen then I'm trying to
add it the tickets which are being filtered based on the color is this clear guys how this
particular functionality is working filter one if there is anyone still who didn't understand they
can give me thumbs down feel free to do it I can repeat it if someone is feeling feeling
overwhelming seeing this logics they can understand this if someone is you know going through web
development for the first time okay now now there is okay I see one thumbs down okay I see
another thumbs down to cool guys give me if you if you're still facing challenge one thing I can
do is that I can I can stay long in doubt session I can explain you understand right yeah great so
I'm expecting this thing I'm expecting this thing to people to react so that I can re-explain things
okay okay cool filtering on basis of what filtering on basis of what user has selected no let me write
to debug and show okay what's happening here just see it here guys now if you see if I if a user
is clicking on green color now inside this toolbox what I'm getting here in selected
toolbox let's just see this now if you see in a selected toolbox color it's light green because
user has clicked light green here now we have to filter all the tickets on the base of light green
now if you see the ticket array we have three tickets so one is light pink the other one is
light green then the other one is light blue so we are supposed to show only one ticket which
is light green in color isn't it so now user selected light green now I'm checking on each
ticket on each ticket what is the color if your color is matching only then add it into this
filter tickets array that's how filter works right is this clear some bit so filtering based
on what you was selected once use once we get this once we get this if you see I'm going through
all the elements now I get only one ticket because there's only one ticket with a light
green color as I've shown you earlier on a ticket array only one thing one ticket this now I am going
into this one I am getting all the tickets again I'm removing each ticket from the dom okay if you
see once I remove all the tickets I'm coming back here I'm coming back here on the filter tickets
I am calling again create ticket function and I'm passing all the tickets whichever are filtered
one okay and adding on to the dom did you understand this flow guys know
how many of you are able to follow up this one now better Abhinav Kartika Ganesh okay
we're able to get this right guys this only one functionality that we have to you know there's
a one fix still there's a one bug I want to point out there is a one bug since we are adding all
the tickets right all the tickets into ticket array now what if user deletes the tickets we
have to remove that from array also right if user is deleting this ticket we have to update
update this particular thing right ticket array did anyone understand this point now while creating
ticket all good while creating ticket we are whatever new ticket user is creating you are
adding into that array good great but what if user is deleting are you taking care of taking care
of this ticket array memory like deleting this is like a database whatever new ticket you are
adding adding it but what if your user is deleting are you deleting that no so now we have to address
this one like once user is clicking any delete right if user is clicking any delete so we have
to take care to remove this one now how can you delete this one how can you think of this thing
let's say if you go for handle remove we are having here ticket hold to get information we
are having it can we pass here since we have ticket ID if we pass ticket ID unique value
here inside the ticket remove and I accept this particular ticket here okay and how many of you
remember splice method array or splice if I have to delete one particular element how can I do that
no firstly I have to get that particular ticket right let's say const get ticket okay inside that
first if I have to get the ticket which have to delete it I have to write a function to it now
let's say no we have this list of array ticket array inside that ticket array
now I have to write it to this array then I have to update and return it okay let's say const
empty then I'll filter through all the existing tickets tickets array dot length once I do this
once I have this array then what I'm supposed to do I have to check for the each ticket array
so ticket arrays ticket ARR inside the ticket ARR dot index dot ticket ID right if it is matching
the current ticket ID okay only if this is matching then first break the loop and update
ticket equal to this ticket information once we do this I'll say that hey return let's say return
ticket now I'll cut this one I'll say that I'll add it here bottom and something that we are
passing here is ticket ID in general what I'm doing it is that from this array whatever array
we are storing all the tickets based on ticket ID getting that object which object this object
whatever we are pushing right whole object that I'm trying to get back okay get the ticket based
on ticket IDs okay now let's say I call this here firstly can you get me the ticket based on
ticket ID and whatever it is returning it let's say we got hold ticket information that we need
to remove once I have this ticket I'll call tickets array dot splice ticket comma one do
you think they should work guys is it firstly did anyone and all of you understand what I was
trying to do here I was just getting the whole ticket using the ticket ID whichever user is
trying to delete it using this method get me that ticket once I get that ticket I'm trying to remove
it using splice method isn't it let's say if this is working fine if this is working fine okay let's
see if this is working fine firstly I I have let's say some gibberish task tasks pink color
let's say I have another task q2 green color okay let me open inspect tool also now if you
see here I have to create another task to see this one okay did I remove console log here yeah
let me add okay if I reload I'll lose all the tickets no worries I will show it by debugging
anyways I lost the tickets once I click save it will auto reloads
now firstly if you see here we have three tickets as we have created three now let's
enable the delete button once I enable the delete button let's go to handle remove let's see what
we are getting inside this one okay and the function here okay once I click this I'm trying
to click the pink ticket ticket has been removed okay did I mess up cannot access ticket before
initialization did we kill this process okay okay I let's say ticket object naming convention
was the issue guys so let's just try to create one ticket and try to verify this state if it
is working fine I try to delete it then I click here now once I do this ticket has
been deleted now if you see we were passing that particular idea because if you see here
only one ticket was there now we are supposed to empty this array right we have to remove
this from element from this area if you now if we go inside the get ticket function let's
say if you are able to get that whole object now that whole object is built and given back to you
once you receive this object you are doing something like a splice function okay I'm
removing this particular object and only remove that one starting from that index remove only
one thing okay once I do that it will be filtered now I have to console log again to show it show
back show to you console dot log after deleting from array
now let's say we clean this up now if you see in the console log I have one ticket and I'll
remove the debuggers as of now we don't need it now once I click this status is working fine let's
I enable this one once I enable delete button and click this if you see after deleting the
array become empty so we handle that edge case so I hope you are able to understand this case how
we are managing how we are storing in the memory and deleting the existing tickets and handling
it now I don't want to further overwhelm you guys because there is a one feature as I've told you
that you know I wanted to cover one more thing on double click of filter color like render all the
tickets like once I use a clicks like double click here or do anything we should be able to
render all the tickets like all the tickets you can get it again from this array itself you'll
have all the articles that are present in array itself do you want me to cover it up and explain
the whole thing or you want me to take it up in next class double on double click I have to
render all the tickets back do you want us to you want me to cover it I see one thumbs up
next class same as I click we can do it now yeah same as I click nothing nothing much new it's
just an five minutes work because already all the parts of the things have been covered it just that
I have to add simple one like four lines of code okay one thing I'll do is that I'll take it up
because in next class I have to explain local storage we can do the poll let me arrange a poll
let's say I also give 30 seconds are fine okay I'm launching the poll guys please select it
50-50 ratio
okay let's let's do it guys let's do this okay won't take much longer now if what I was saying
is that if you see from the requirement point of view I am still saying it that on double
click of this any color we are supposed to render all the tickets now we already added
event listeners to them and we added event listeners here itself we got an access to
toolbox colors and inside this we are adding all the events listeners to each each one of them
right now for this event listener we are listening to click but we want to listen to double click
so what I'll do right I'll just say that I want to listen for each color
double click for double click similar to click we have dbl click right do you all know this
if someone want to listen to double click it's just that same you have to just this
write down double click right plain simple straightforward now once you do this once you
do this you have to again when whatever tickets are there on the existing screen you have to
clean that existing screen right I'm trying to clean that existing screen same method copy
paste it same method copy paste it clean the existing screen now once cleaned up
again create for all things as we have done this for the filtered array I'll do it on ticket array
dot forage same logic let's try copy this I paste it here nothing else sorted it didn't even take
10 minutes but for re-explaining it will take it so on click of double click I say that if there
are on some on screen someone have filtered and there is one ticket showing I am saying that remove
that thing and I'll I'll recreate and render everything okay let's see this if this is working
fine okay I have one task of pink color let's say I have another task of green color
so I have another task of blue in color now three colors are there now let's say
we can filter based on pink green blue and black everything is fine
long black we don't have anything now if I click double click if I click double click
let's say I'll show you once a while we'll walk through remove all the other break points then go back
this is the part it should get created okay now once I click double click event
let's say I'm clicking on pink color two times I clicked it came into this execution and it is
working on removing this pink color first if you see it will remove this pink color okay inside this
dome whatever it is rendered it will remove pink color once pink color is removed in the ticket array
here I have three tickets one is in light pink one is in light green one is in light blue let's
create back all of them
simple and straightforward isn't it once you understand one third of logic
everything revolves around that part sir
are you able to follow up guys are you did you understand this one
great great great
so guys one thing I'll do is that I covered whatever I want to cover for today
okay next class I'll show you like if you if you see this one right what's happening currently if
I go and refresh we are not able to persist any ticket so we will work on local storage but we
have to understand different types of storages we'll introduce to that topic then we'll come
back and implement that part here okay so I'll commit this code
what we have covered filter
filter based
rendering
git push now so I'll talk on few things guys I'll start the doubt session I'll talk on few things
okay so I would request everyone to stay back in doubt session for five minutes I want to show
you few things okay
if someone want to go they are also open to go like if you want to leave but I want to talk
about something like event bubbling concept firstly then I'll come back and pick though
all the questions okay now
give me a second I'll have water
now in last class Kiran Kiran are you there in the class
do I have him
okay I don't think he's there but what he suggested hey can't we use event bubbling why do you want to
add like handle remove during ticket creation what if I click on this main container itself
and you try to identify okay what I have clicked on okay now so what happens in event bubbling is
what happens in event bubbling is that let's say I try to explain on the ipad once for the
few people I've seen that few people don't understand it so I'll try to explain it now
let's say we have this main content area
this is the main content area in this we have multiple tickets
now once I have this multiple tickets I was adding event listener to this one
event listener to this one event listeners to this one so his idea was why are you adding
three event listeners if we can accept we can do it implement functionality by only one
adding a listener here which is apparent to all the tickets can we do it
but how we can do it there's some concept called event two concepts event bubbling
and event capturing
like when we say bubble bubble forms this way
right going from center area to outward now same way when user clicks on this ticket let's say user
clicks on this ticket if you add a listener to this one even the code inside this listener
will execute
that's what event bubbling talks about is this logic clear to everyone like how event bubbling works
right I see one two three okay I can show you the demo also like how it works
okay now I connected script one file instead of handle remote right or doing it this way
now let's say I create some two three tasks
I've created three tasks now I go here
I come back here let's say I enable first delete button once I enable it
if you come here and see in this logic now I didn't add event listener to the tickets but
I added it to the main container main ticket container and I am just listening to the click
element now let's see what happens here firstly if I click on this ticket let's say if I anyone
I click on this ticket okay now I am checking whether ticket button is enabled
delete button is enabled yes delete button is enabled so it will go inside this condition
first if else condition okay then it will check firstly what I clicked what is this event target
what I clicked I clicked on something called ticket ID because I clicked here on the yellow part
I'm checking like hey on this ticket ID if this particular ticket ID existing in this child classes
yeah that's there that's there once if it goes inside if condition I say remove its parent node
when I say parent node what do I exactly mean by ticket ID is like if you go into elements
if I go into the second ticket which I clicked on I clicked this particular part A5N1 I'm going to
its parent to ticket container I'm saying that remove that particular ticket container itself
let's see if this is working fine let's see if this is working fine if I click play now do you
see that A5 got deleted because this happened because event bubbling concept we didn't go by
particular now if I let's see if I instead of ticket ID earlier I clicked on ticket ID if I
click on this container part let's say click on this container part even now our parent main
container which is the whole container for all tickets are still listening that click event
it received that click event now again it checks that hey delete button is still too
now it goes inside this condition now once again it checks what is the thing you clicked
you clicked on something called ticket container itself whole container you have clicked outside
the task area because task area is only available when you are clicking on edit part okay once you
are done that it will check whether that part is true like whether you are having this ticket container
by default in inside this it is a child element if it is child element it will remove the parent
so it's not a child element it's ticket itself with a ticket container so it will go into else
if condition if you see else if condition ticket container and we are comparing with ticket container
then it will go and remove that particular target element itself instead of removing the parent
because something we got access to now is this whole ticket itself okay now let's see if I click
play the ticket got removed wholly now there's a third scenario I click on ticket banner like which
is a band on the top level let's click on this one now again this will go from the child parent
node let's see this what's what we are getting here if you see I hover over it again I'm getting
ticket color yeah ticket color if you see I am checking for ticket color okay I'm checking for
the particular colors also light green light blue now what is the color I got I got something like
light pink now light pink is there here okay it's not there but you can add it
okay we can add it and you will execute this particular thing it will like if you add it
here in the light pink then it will remove I hope you got the basic idea like how that
event bubbling you can leverage and still build these futures rather than adding multiple event
listers I hope this point is clear to everyone
now guys I open for your doubts if you want me to repeat anything if you want me to talk on anything
I can repeat and talk do let me know what you want me to talk on
is there something that you didn't understand from today's class or the whole thing or part
of curriculum or are you facing any challenge do let me know I can share some thoughts on that
my thoughts but before that did you understand today's class completely
how many of you understood today's class I see only one thumbs up come on guys
thank you so I hope you enjoyed you know we picked it up this project because it's more of a
event listener stuff like how few add event listeners how you go to child elements how
can you manipulate existing and adding things there's nothing much of logic here we try to
we try to make it as simple as this one and if you see it's it's all about
if you search only right this method add event listener it's nine times right nine times we
added event listener if you even if you go on the page you can see what are the nine times like
one is plus one is cross one are these buttons then you have a lock icon then you have text area
icon then you have color or that status changing status icon so all these parts you had event
listeners and any user doing any interaction with them on on interacting with them we are making
some changes on that just that said it will come by when you practice it you will get used to it
okay so you need not to worry just give some time try to see that code offline okay if you face any
challenge to let me know during that moment also thank you manishara
guys did you enjoy this project i need your feedback like is this good enough
for beginner level like when we teach whole things html css and down
um
no reactions okay i got only muneshwara's comment but i hope you enjoyed it i hope you understood
uh like how how like because now if you see if this project was so difficult like if i build
this with react right if i build this whole functionality with react i have took uh more
than let's say three classes no nine hours or say six hours to range of nine hours six to nine if
i build this with react i can do it in three to four hours not more than that i you will be able
to understand uh more easily because that's what declarative way of coding does to you
so now if you see i'm adding event listener i'm going manually selecting item dom item query
selectors all these things will be done you know smoothly
okay we'll see that in future someone also can replicate this one
um yeah a complete website will be good cover for html css js uh yeah so one thing you can do
is this this project you can also deploy on github pages so we thought of you know doing it two
projects one is portfolio which will share recording should have been shared but i kept
pinging that person person was on leave so by tomorrow i'll make sure that you get that project
yeah i know that muneshwara not retarded because that also get right right uh the person who was
supposed to do it he was on leave okay he was on leave because now he will be adding to your
like your batch like uh and so basically we thought of building two projects uh and
few mission coding uh problems so these are the two basic projects and then mission coding
because on uh full uh end-to-end development right on html css js
it would be more based on uh machine coding problems
uh if we didn't click the color while creating a ticket it will make it as black if we're clicking
one color okay let's let's try this thing uh i click something query and i click directly option
if you see black is right default okay but if we click one color again creating a new
okay firstly if we click any color while creating a ticket will make it as black that's okay
that's okay but if we click any one color when create ticket and again creating a new ticket
right
okay now uh if you say so let's see this my first statement was validated second statement i click
pink and i select option then i come back i uh do this i don't select color i click again this thing
now i got the pink okay uh no by default we can we have to stick it to one color
we'll fix this bug okay whenever user is not selecting it we have to make sure that uh
there's a one consistent color all the time okay one way we can do is that uh since this is a model
priority color uh you know black color while creating a ticket
let's say here here is where we are calling it now we might be updating this color somewhere
let me check this
now user clicked it that's fine when he's reopening right when he's reopening and typing it down
okay
one thing we can do is like update this once you are doing this one update this as black
so it this will be done this will be automatically taken care now let's let's try to read this do
this one i select query pink color i click option then i take this one again do query ui
then if i do this i'm getting black i'm not getting pink
this is fine kabir thank you for pointing it out
just uh resetting while resetting you have to update that reset as a because we are doing here
reset right whatever reset we're doing we have to handle there
so guys if all things are fine we can close the session for today
thank you for joining see you in the next class where we'll be discussing different types of
storages in browser so that concept should be would be important for you once you understand
those concepts right then we'll like you know do apply those knowledge of local storage here in
the application then revisit this whole application and then close this project okay
okay i hope to see you everyone in the next class on saturday
please do attend it or try to make it as simple as possible for you
okay thank you all have a great night take rest
bye guys good night good night kabir
thank you sambit good night munesh for all
good night sambit so guys see you on saturday bye
you